♪Minum ibun♪
♪미눔 이분♪
♪Your roots are holding tight♪
♪당신의 뿌리는 굳건히 자리잡고 있습니다♪
♪On this land♪
♪이 땅에서♪
♪Mengejar ombak♪
♪멘게자르 옴박♪
♪My leaves fly by♪
♪나의 나뭇잎이 날아간다♪
♪The border of thousands of stones♪
♪수천개의 돌의 경계♪
♪Looking at each other from afar♪
♪멀리서 서로를 바라보며♪
♪The edge of the cliff is♪
♪절벽의 끝은♪
♪Live together forever♪
♪영원히 함께 살아요♪
♪When we meet and part again♪
♪만나고 또 헤어지면♪
♪When we depend on each other and are far away♪
♪서로 의지 하고 멀리 떨어져 있을 때♪
♪I never forget♪
♪절대 잊지 않아요♪
♪The light reflected on the sword and knife♪
♪검과 칼에 반사되는 빛♪
♪Light up the dim sky♪
♪어두운 하늘을 밝혀주세요♪
♪Abandoned dreams♪
♪버려진 꿈♪
♪Shattered in the wind♪
♪바람에 부서지네♪
♪Against the direction of the wind and waves♪
♪바람과 파도의 반대방향♪
♪See thousands of ships crossing♪
♪수천 척의 배가 건너가는 모습을 보세요♪
♪This world changes♪
♪이 세상은 변한다♪
♪A suit of armor with make-up swinging in the wind♪
♪화장한 갑옷이 바람에 휘날리네요♪
♪Drinking ice, the blood is hard to be cold, dreaming of having fun in love♪
♪얼음을 마시고 피가 식지 않고 즐거운 사랑을 꿈꾸며♪
♪Just wish you were by my side♪
♪ 당신이 내 곁에 있었으면 좋겠어요 ♪
♪Don't waste spring time♪
♪봄날을 낭비하지 마세요♪
♪Trees reach the sky, roots connect, your friends uphold justice in the world♪
♪나무는 하늘에 닿고, 뿌리는 연결되고, 친구들은 세상의 정의를 수호합니다♪
♪Seeing the light flickering on the shoulder♪
♪어깨에 깜빡이는 빛을 보고♪
♪No regrets in this world♪
♪세상에 후회는 없어♪
=Wonderland of Love=
=사랑의 원더랜드=
=Episode 24=
=에피소드 24=
(Boundary Barrel)
(경계 배럴)
Governor.
지사.
Already sent them?
이미 보냈나요?
When Mrs. Wei got into the vehicle,
웨이 부인이 차량에 탑승했을 때,
he was reluctant to leave here.
그는 여기를 떠나는 것을 꺼려했습니다.
He cried sadly
그는 슬프게 울었다
and wanted to accompany the governor
주지사와 동행하고 싶었습니다
to remain on the Tong Border.
통 국경(Tong Border)에 남아있습니다.
I advise madam
나는 부인에게 조언합니다
to take good care of the young master.
젊은 주인을 잘 보살피기 위해.
After this war is over,
이 전쟁이 끝난 후,
they will be brought back here.
그들은 여기로 다시 돌아올 것입니다.
Kali ini, Tentera Zhenxi
칼리 이니, 텐테라 젠시
conspired with the Cui Family Army.
Cui Family Army와 공모했습니다.
This war will determine life and death.
이 전쟁이 삶과 ​​죽음을 결정할 것이다.
It will end.
끝날 것이다.
Somewhat
약간
we will not come back here again.
우리는 여기에 다시 돌아오지 않을 것입니다.
(West Door)
(서쪽 문)
Chang'er.
체인저.
Tuan Shiqi.
투안시치.
One two three.
하나 둘 셋.
(Boundary Barrel)
(경계 배럴)
Governor. The Zhenxi Army allied with the Cui Family Army
지사. 진희군은 추이씨족군과 동맹을 맺었다
and attack here.
그리고 여기를 공격해.
We protect you first.
우리는 당신을 먼저 보호합니다.
As long as we live,
우리가 사는 한,
we still have a chance.
우리에겐 아직 기회가 있습니다.
Go?
가다?
Where else can we go?
또 어디로 갈 수 있나요?
Exit the Capital City of Xichang
수도인 시창(Xichang)을 빠져나와
and escaped from the Tong Border.
통 국경에서 탈출했습니다.
Now, we're out of the Barrel Border again.
이제 우리는 다시 배럴 보더(Barrel Border)를 벗어났습니다.
Where else can we go?
또 어디로 갈 수 있나요?
Governor.
지사.
The Zhenxi Army allied with the Cui Family Army.
Zhenxi 군대는 Cui Family 군대와 동맹을 맺었습니다.
The enemy is many times our number.
적은 우리 수의 몇 배나 됩니다.
If we stay at the Tong Border,
통 보더(Tong Border)에 묵으면,
we can still survive for a while.
우리는 아직 한동안 살아남을 수 있어요.
However, out of nowhere
그러나 갑자기
The Zhenxi army entered the border.
Zhenxi 군대가 국경에 진입했습니다.
How do we survive?
우리는 어떻게 살아남나요?
Both armies are fighting and now it is too late.
두 군대가 싸우고 있는데 이제는 너무 늦었습니다.
Governor, let's go.
주지사님, 가세요.
During the Battle of the Han Sea,
한해해전 당시
the Khagan's soldiers are ten times more numerous than ours.
카간의 병사들은 우리 병사들보다 10배 더 많습니다.
I lead the army to resist
나는 군대를 이끌고 저항한다
and blood stained my battle shirt.
그리고 피가 내 전투 셔츠를 더럽혔습니다.
I almost lost one of my arms.
나는 팔 중 하나를 잃을 뻔했습니다.
Didn't I still win?
나 아직도 이기지 않았어?
There are tens of thousands of soldiers in the city
도시에는 수만 명의 군인이 있습니다.
still against the enemy.
여전히 적과 맞서고 있습니다.
I can't ignore them.
나는 그들을 무시할 수 없습니다.
I will not go
난 안가
Bring his great-grandson here.
그의 증손자를 여기로 데려오세요.
Of.
의.
Sun Jing.
쑨징.
It's reached this stage,
이 단계에 이르렀고,
you still refuse to give up?
아직도 포기를 거부하고 있나요?
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
Now, the Tong border has been invaded.
이제 통(Tong) 국경이 침공당했습니다.
You will definitely lose.
당신은 확실히 잃을 것입니다.
If you release his great-grandson,
그 증손자를 풀어주면
i won't kill you
난 당신을 죽이지 않을 거예요
On that day, your father
그날 네 아버지는
crawling and pleading in front of me.
내 앞에 기어가며 애원하는 것.
If he didn't pretend to be dead and run away,
죽은 척 하고 도망가지 않았다면 ,
he has no chance
그에겐 기회가 없어
to be the illegitimate emperor in the capital.
수도의 불법 황제가 되는 것 .
Today, his great-grandson is in my hands.
오늘은 그의 증손자가 내 손에 있습니다.
I am the rightful emperor.
나는 정당한 황제이다.
In your words,
당신의 말에 따르면,
do you want me to hand over his great-grandson?
내가 그 사람의 증손자를 넘겨주길 바라나요?
What do you want?
당신은 무엇을 원합니까?
You and your army
당신과 당신의 군대
retreat from the Tong Border now.
지금 통국경에서 후퇴하라.
Tell the illegitimate emperor in the capital to issue orders
수도에 있는 불법 황제에게 명령을 내리라고 전하세요
and tell everyone
그리고 모두에게 말해요
that he ascended the throne in the wrong way.
그가 잘못된 방법으로 왕위에 올랐다는 것입니다 .
He will return the throne to his great-grandson.
그는 증손자에게 왕위를 돌려줄 것이다 .
Given the current state of border warfare,
현재 국경전의 상황을 보면 ,
it feels like you
너 같은 느낌이야
not worth negotiating with me.
나와 협상할 가치가 없어.
Mari.
마리.
(West Door)
(서쪽 문)
Li Ni.
리니.
This boy is the only one
이 소년은 유일한 사람입니다
descendant of the late crown prince.
고(故) 왕세자의 후손.
In your Li Family,
귀하의 리 가족에서는
he is the only legitimate descendant.
그는 유일한 적법한 후손이다.
If he were killed today,
만약 오늘 그 사람이 죽었다면,
how do you want to be responsible
너는 어떻게 책임지고 싶니?
in front of everyone?
모두 앞에서?
how is your father,
아버지는 잘 계시나요?
illegitimate emperor
불법 황제
should be responsible?
책임을 져야 하나?
Do not mind me!
내 말은 신경쓰지 마세요!
Kill Rebel Sun!
반란군 태양을 죽여라!
Restore the peace of the country!
조국의 평화를 회복하라!
Kill him!
그를 죽여!
Sun Jing!
쑨징!
You are a famous warrior.
당신은 유명한 전사입니다.
I didn't think you considered a little boy as your protector!
나는 당신이 어린 소년을 당신의 보호자로 생각하지 않았다고 생각했습니다!
You will be laughed at.
당신은 비웃을 것입니다.
No need to stimulate me.
나를 자극할 필요는 없어요.
If you don't back down,
물러서지 않으면,
I will act.
나는 행동할 것이다.
Stop!
멈추다!
I will save his great-grandson
내가 그의 증손자를 구하리라
at the cost of my life.
내 목숨을 희생해서.
- Tuan Shiqi!
- 투안시치!
Mr. Shiqi, you can't do that!
Shiqi 씨, 그렇게 할 수 없습니다!
Do not mind me.
신경쓰지 마세요.
Jangan, Tuan Shiqi.
장안, 투안시치.
Kill Rebel Sun, recover...
Rebel Sun을 처치하고 회복하세요...
Tuan Shiqi!
투안시치!
Don't be like that. Back here.
그렇게 하지 마십시오. 여기로 돌아오세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
King Qin is really brave.
진왕은 정말 용감해요.
I will keep my promise.
나는 약속을 지킬 것이다.
King of Qin.
진(秦)나라 왕.
Kill yourself.
자살하세요.
Master Shiqi, don't be like that!
Shiqi 선생님, 그러지 마세요!
Tuan Shiqi!
투안시치!
- Master Shiqi! - Just attack!
- 시치 선생님! - 그냥 공격하세요!
Abang Shiqi. Jangan!
아방시치 장안!
Jangan, Abang Shiqi!
장안, 아방시치!
Don't!
하지 않다!
Tuan Shiqi, jangan!
Tuan Shiqi, 장안!
King of Qin.
진(秦)나라 왕.
His great-grandson on Sun Jing's side is fake.
Sun Jing 측의 증손자는 가짜입니다.
The boy I brought here
내가 데려온 그 아이
then his great-grandson is true.
그렇다면 그의 증손자가 사실이다.
What?
무엇?
Li Ni.
리니.
It's okay if you refuse to save his great-grandchild.
증손자를 구하는 것을 거부 해도 괜찮습니다 .
You don't have to play evil tricks.
사악한 속임수를 쓸 필요는 없습니다.
You want to use a fake great-grandson
가짜 증손자를 이용하고 싶다
to get a chance
기회를 얻기 위해
kill his great-grandson legally.
증손자를 합법적으로 죽여라.
Governor.
지사.
You mean, this boy I brought is his fake great-grandson?
내가 데려온 이 아이가 그 사람의 가짜 증손자란 말인가 ?
How do you prove it?
어떻게 증명하나요?
that you captured the real great-grandson?
진짜 증손자를 잡았다고 ?
His great-grandson has
그의 증손자는
seal of the late crown prince.
고(故) 황태자의 인장.
I robbed people and their seals
나는 사람과 인장을 훔쳤습니다.
from Han Chang.
한창 출신.
If you're in doubt,
의심스럽다면,
no need to negotiate anymore.
더 이상 협상할 필요가 없습니다.
I will continue to kill him.
나는 계속해서 그를 죽일 것입니다.
Stop. Put down your knife!
멈추다. 칼을 내려놔!
Take action. Governor.
행동을 취하다. 지사.
The governor never doubted
주지사는 결코 의심하지 않았다
Panglima Yunchang, Han Chang?
판글리마 윤창, 한창?
He was the old nobleman of the late crown prince who was so obedient.
그는 너무나 순종적인 고(故) 세자의 노귀족이었다 .
After you kidnapped his great-grandson,
그의 증손자를 납치한 후,
why is he not tracking you?
그 사람은 왜 당신을 추적하지 않는 거죠?
and gather people to save his great-grandson?
증손자를 구하기 위해 사람들을 모으겠다고 ?
The seal of the late crown prince,
고(故) 황태자 의 인장 ,
mengapa Panglima Yunchang
멘가파 팡리마 윤창
put it down
내려 놔
on this boy?
이 소년한테?
He won't know
그 사람은 모를 거야
that you can identify
당신이 식별할 수 있는
the identity of this boy
이 소년의 정체
after getting this thing.
이 물건을 받고 나면.
There is indeed a possibility of that.
실제로 그럴 가능성이 있습니다.
All soldiers will be promoted and given a reward of ten thousand tahil
모든 군인은 진급하고 1만 타힐의 보상을 받습니다.
after killing Sun Jing!
Sun Jing을 죽인 후!
Attack!
공격!
Take his great-grandson to go first.
증손자를 데리고 먼저 가십시오.
He's still useful.
그는 여전히 유용합니다.
His great-grandson.
그의 증손자.
Fifth Han.
다섯번째 그.
It's ok.
괜찮아요.
I came to save you.
나는 당신을 구하기 위해 왔습니다.
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
Sun Jing.
쑨징.
On the day you killed the emperor,
네가 황제를 죽인 날,
have you ever imagined
상상해 본 적 있나요?
that you will be defeated badly?
당신이 심하게 패배할 것이라고?
King of Qin.
진(秦)나라 왕.
Keep killing
계속 죽여
just such a rebel.
정말 반항아에요.
I am highly skilled.
나는 고도로 숙련되어 있습니다.
If I hadn't been poisoned,
내가 중독되지 않았다면,
no matter how many people
사람이 아무리 많아도
not comparable to me
나랑 비교불가
Ignorant boy.
무지한 소년.
Don't you try to kill me.
나를 죽이려고 하지 마세요.
I won't let you do it.
나는 당신이 그것을 할 수 없습니다.
This pair of jed counters
이 쌍의 제드 카운터
really smooth
정말 부드럽다
One person takes half.
한 사람이 반을 차지합니다.
I will use it forever.
나는 그것을 영원히 사용할 것이다.
I will not ignore you.
나는 당신을 무시하지 않을 것입니다.
We will not be separated.
우리는 헤어지지 않을 것입니다.
(In the first year of Tiantai, Dayu Dynasty,)
(다유왕조 천태 원년 )
(Sun Jing is defeated at the Tong Border)
(손정은 통국경에서 패배한다)
(and killed himself.)
(그리고 자살했다.)
(His wife, Mrs. Wei)
(그의 아내 웨이 부인)
(and his eldest son)
(그리고 그의 큰 아들)
(caught on the run.)
(도망가다 붙잡혔다.)
(Since then, Sun Jing's rebellion)
(그 이후로 Sun Jing의 반란)
(completely sedated.)
(완전히 진정되었습니다.)
Be careful.
조심하세요.
Take it there.
거기로 가져가세요.
Mari.
마리.
How?
어떻게?
- Slowly. - We go there.
- 느리게. - 우리는 거기로 간다.
Save this.
이것을 저장하세요.
Put it there.
거기에 넣어.
Slowly.
느리게.
- Come on. - Let me help.
- 어서 해봐요. - 제가 도와드릴게요.
There's more there.
거기에 더 많은 것이 있습니다.
Mari.
마리.
Lieutenant.
대장 보좌.
Why?
왜?
Someone kidnapped his great-grandson in the chaos earlier.
앞서 누군가가 혼란 속에서 증손자를 납치했습니다 .
- Quickly tell people to chase him. - Yes.
- 재빨리 사람들에게 그를 쫓아오라고 말하세요. - 예.
How about King Qin?
진왕(秦王)은 어떻습니까?
Let me tell him.
내가 그에게 말해줄게.
Go away.
저리 가요.
Good.
좋은.
Ying.
잉.
You are struggling.
당신은 어려움을 겪고 있습니다.
With your help,
당신의 도움으로,
only then did I find his real great-grandson.
그제서야 그의 진짜 증손자를 찾았습니다.
Now, Sun Jing is dead.
이제 Sun Jing은 죽었습니다.
We just need to bring his great-grandson
그 사람 증손자를 데려오면 돼
back to the palace
다시 궁전으로
Shiqi.
시치.
I must reveal something
뭔가를 밝혀야 해
against you
당신에 대한
The boy I brought
내가 데려온 애
is fake.
가짜입니다.
His real great-grandson
그의 진짜 증손자
indeed the boy kidnapped by Sun Jing.
실제로 Sun Jing에게 납치된 소년 입니다.
I have arranged people
사람들을 정리했어요
looking for an opportunity in the chaos to save his real grandchild.
혼란 속에서 진짜 손자를 구할 기회를 찾고 있습니다.
However, I don't think anyone acted first.
그런데 누구도 먼저 행동한 적이 없는 것 같아요 .
We must think of a way quickly
빨리 방법을 생각해내야 해
and chasing his real great-grandson.
그리고 그의 진짜 증손자를 쫓는다.
Shiqi!
시치!
Wake up.
깨우다.
Go away.
저리 가요.
Let's count.
세어 보자.
Strengthen again.
다시 강화하세요.
Transport here. Go away.
여기로 운송하세요. 저리 가요.
Master Shiqi, we can't catch up.
Shiqi 선생님, 우리는 따라잡을 수 없습니다.
They were able to save his great-grandson in a chaotic situation.
그들은 혼란스러운 상황에서 증손자를 구할 수 있었습니다 .
Their actions are very fast.
그들의 행동은 매우 빠릅니다.
Presumably they were Commander Han and his subordinates.
아마도 한사령관과 그의 부하들이었을 것이다 .
It seems that his great-grandson is safe...
증손자는 무사한 것 같은데...
How can we be sure that they are Han Chang
그들이 한창인지 어떻게 확신할 수 있는가?
and his subordinates?
그리고 그의 부하들은?
What if he was kidnapped by the bad guys?
만약 그가 악당들에게 납치됐다면?
I once made a promise with Mistress Xiao
나는 샤오씨와 약속한 적이 있다.
to save his great-grandson.
증손자를 구하기 위해.
However, you brought a fake majesty's great-grandson
그런데 가짜 폐하의 증손자를 데려오셨군요.
to trick Sun Jing earlier.
Sun Jing을 더 일찍 속이기 위해.
Have you ever thought that if he trusts you,
그가 당신을 신뢰 한다면 ,
he might do evil things to his real grandchild?
진짜 손자에게 나쁜 짓을 할 수도 있지 않을까요 ?
I used to think about it.
나는 그것에 대해 생각하곤했습니다.
Since you know it's high risk,
위험성이 크다는 걸 알기 때문에
why are you doing it again?
왜 또 그러는 거야?
I have considered it many times in my heart.
나는 그것을 마음 속으로 여러 번 생각해 보았습니다 .
I have 80 percent confidence
나는 80%의 자신감을 가지고 있다
to convince Sun Jing
Sun Jing을 설득하기 위해
and save his great-grandson.
그리고 그의 증손자를 구해주세요.
80 percent?
80퍼센트?
What about the other 20 percent?
나머지 20%는 어떻습니까?
It's good if we
우리라면 좋지
can save his great-grandson.
증손자를 구할 수 있습니다.
If an accident occurs,
사고가 발생하면,
it's my fault,
그것은 내 잘못이야,
nothing to do with you
너랑은 아무 상관 없어
An accident
사고
is your fault
네 잘못이야
and have nothing to do with me?
그리고 나랑 아무 상관도 없어?
Shiqi.
시치.
It must be me
나임에 틀림없어
explain everything?
다 설명해?
Don't you understand it too?
당신도 이해하지 못합니까?
If you really
만약 당신이 정말로
brought his great-grandson back to the capital,
증손자를 다시 수도로 데려왔고,
state of the palace
궁전의 상태
will experience turmoil,
혼란을 겪게 될 것이다.
not?
아니다?
I understand your thoughts.
나는 당신의 생각을 이해합니다.
You want him to appoint his great-grandson as crown prince.
당신은 그가 자신의 증손자를 왕세자로 임명하기를 원합니다.
However, have you ever thought about this?
그런데, 혹시 이것에 대해 생각해 본 적 있나요?
Our country has just become stable and the people's situation is not guaranteed.
우리나라는 이제 막 안정된 상태에 이르렀고 국민의 형편도 보장되지 않습니다.
Does everyone
모두가 그렇습니까?
will agree with your thoughts?
네 생각에 동의하겠어?
Can the palace
궁전이 가능할까요?
experiencing turmoil
혼란을 겪고 있다
one more time?
한번 더?
You are full of justification and reason.
당신은 정당성과 이성이 가득합니다.
Why didn't you consult me ​​first?
왜 나한테 먼저 상의하지 않았어 ?
Because you know
당신이 알고 있기 때문에
that I won't agree, right?
난 동의하지 않을 거에요, 그렇죠?
Of.
의.
His Highness is very brave.
전하께서는 매우 용감하십니다.
I don't deserve it
난 그럴 자격이 없어
intervened earlier.
더 일찍 개입했습니다.
I have to let you sacrifice yourself
네가 희생하도록 놔둬야 해
and praised by all.
그리고 모두에게 칭찬을 받았습니다.
When I pass through here,
여기를 지나갈 때,
I will too
나도 그럴 거야
burn incense for you.
당신을 위해 향을 태워주세요.
Lieutenant.
대장 보좌.
Everything is my fault.
모든 것이 내 잘못입니다.
I could not save his great-grandson.
나는 그의 증손자를 구할 수 없었다 .
Nothing to do with you.
당신과는 아무 상관이 없습니다.
I told you
내가 말했잖아
bring people to save his great-grandson,
증손자를 구하기 위해 사람들을 데려오세요 .
but I didn't think so
하지만 난 그렇게 생각하지 않았어
there's a scout there.
거기 스카우트가 있어요.
Somewhat
약간
they are Han Commanders
그들은 한족 사령관이다
and his subordinates.
그리고 그의 부하들.
Of course you can't fight them.
물론 그들과 싸울 수는 없습니다.
How is your wound?
상처는 어때요?
I am fine.
괜찮아요.
Kata Is Duo,
듀오가 말했지?
King Qin scolded you in front of everyone
진왕이 모든 사람 앞에서 당신을 꾸짖었습니다.
and argue with you.
그리고 당신과 논쟁하십시오.
Don't mention his name.
그 사람 이름은 언급하지 마세요.
Sun Jing left in a hurry.
순진이는 서둘러 떠났다.
He continued
그는 계속했다
set fire to the entire reading room.
독서실 전체에 불을 질렀습니다.
Most of the items inside were also burned.
내부 물품 도 대부분 불에 탔습니다.
I bring people
나는 사람들을 데려온다
find all this
이걸 다 찾아봐
under the rubble.
잔해 아래.
Finally, I know that there are people in the drawing room
드디어 응접실에 사람이 있다는 걸 알았네요
conspired with Sun Jing secretly.
Sun Jing과 비밀리에 공모했습니다.
They are often in contact.
그들은 종종 연락을 합니다.
However, no name is written on this letter.
하지만 이 편지에는 이름이 적혀 있지 않습니다 .
After all, they use secret terms.
결국 그들은 비밀 용어를 사용합니다.
So, we haven't seen it yet
그럼 우리 아직 못 봤잖아
this guy for a while.
이 사람은 한동안.
Shiqi.
시치.
After returning to Xichang Capital,
Xichang Capital로 돌아온 후,
we still need to be careful.
아직은 조심해야 해요.
Of.
의.
Li Ni occupies the Tong Border
리니(Li Ni)가 통(Tong) 국경을 점령하다
and sent people to report him to the palace quickly.
그리고 사람을 보내어 빨리 궁에 보고하라고 했습니다 .
He brought Sun Jing's body back again.
그는 Sun Jing의 시체를 다시 가져 왔습니다.
All the dignitaries praised him in the ballirung seri.
모든 고위 인사들은 발리룽 세리에서 그를 칭찬했습니다.
He made another big contribution.
그는 또 하나의 큰 공헌을 했습니다.
As his brother,
그의 형제로서,
it's hard for me to compete with him.
그와 경쟁하기가 어렵습니다.
It feels like the Eastern Palace
동궁 같은 느낌이에요
will fall into Li Ni's hands.
리니의 손에 넘어갈 것이다.
There is an extraordinary person
특이한 사람이 있네
want to meet the noble.
귀족을 만나고 싶습니다.
He sent people to fetch the noble many times.
그는 귀족을 데려오라고 사람들을 여러 번 보냈습니다.
I can't stand him
나는 그를 참을 수 없다
and meet him once.
그리고 그 사람을 한 번 만나보세요.
He said,
그는 말했다,
he has a great way
그 사람 좋은 방법이 있어
and can help His Majesty.
폐하를 도울 수 있습니다.
This person said his surname was Liu.
이 사람은 자기 성이 Liu라고 했어요.
He was once Cui Yi's adopted son.
그는 한때 Cui Yi의 입양아였습니다.
After I talked to him,
그 사람과 이야기를 나눈 후,
I found that his thoughts were profound
나는 그의 생각이 심오하다는 것을 알았다
and have such a background.
그리고 그런 배경을 가지고 있어요.
This person must be hostile to the Cui Family.
이 사람은 Cui 가족에게 적대적인 사람임에 틀림없습니다.
We can use it.
우리는 그것을 사용할 수 있습니다.
I've been wanting to see you for a long time, Young Master Liu.
오랫동안 뵙고 싶었습니다, 류영사님.
His Highness praised me too much.
전하께서 저를 너무 칭찬하셨습니다.
His Highness will not want to see me.
전하께서는 나를 만나고 싶어하지 않으실 것입니다.
Now, I'm just one
이제 나는 단지 하나일 뿐이야
which is nothing.
그것은 아무것도 아니다.
Since you are nothing,
당신은 아무것도 아니기 때문에,
how do you want to help me?
나를 어떻게 도와주고 싶니?
The King of Qin took back the Tong Border
진왕이 통국경을 되찾았다.
and defeat Sun Jing.
Sun Jing을 물리칩니다.
This is a great service.
이것은 훌륭한 서비스입니다.
After he returned to the capital,
그는 수도로 돌아온 후,
it must be him
그 사람이 틀림없어
want to get the East Palace.
동궁을 얻고 싶다.
As his brother,
그의 형제로서,
doesn't the noble one feel the danger?
고귀한 사람은 위험을 느끼지 않습니까?
My eldest brother is still there.
내 큰 형은 아직 거기 있어요.
Usually, the eldest son will be appointed.
일반적으로 장남이 임명됩니다.
Li Ni didn't stand a chance.
Li Ni는 기회가 없었습니다.
What if Li Ni
만약 리니라면?
married Cui Yi's only child,
최이의 외동딸과 결혼했고,
Cui Family Army
추이 가문 군대
will obey Li Ni's instructions
Li Ni의 지시를 따르겠습니다.
seperti Tentera Zhenxi?
별도의 Tentera Zhenxi?
At that time,
그때에,
even the emperor
심지어 황제도
unable to handle King Qin.
진왕(秦王)을 감당할 수 없다.
Even the noble can't seize the Eastern Palace anymore.
이제 귀족도 동궁을 함락시킬 수 없습니다.
Even the honorable
명예로운 사람이라도
can't be
그럴 수 없어
the prince relaxed again.
왕자는 다시 긴장을 풀었다.
Li Ni will marry Cui's only daughter?
Li Ni는 Cui의 외동딸과 결혼할 것인가 ?
They are already in personal contact.
그들은 이미 개인적인 접촉을 하고 있습니다.
If not,
그렇지 않다면,
why the Cui Family Army
왜 추이 가문 군대인가?
go save Pei Yuan
페이위안을 구해줄게
just with a letter from King Qin?
진왕의 편지만으로 ?
Why did Cui Yi surrender Changzhou
최의는 왜 창저우를 항복시켰는가?
just because King Qin promised
진왕이 약속했기 때문에
to bestow the title of Commander-in-Chief Weiyang worthless?
웨이양 총사령관 이라는 칭호를 무가치하게 주려고 ?
Mengapa Tentera Zhenxi
멘가파 텐테라 젠시
willing to attack the Tong Border
통 국경을 공격할 의지가 있다
with the Cui Family Army?
Cui Family Army와 함께?
Oh it's like that.
아 그렇군요.
Actually, His Highness had already thought carefully.
사실 전하께서는 이미 신중하게 생각하고 계셨습니다.
Is that noble
그게 고상한 걸까요
want to send people
사람들을 보내고 싶어
to kill the King of Qin
진왕을 죽이려고
on his way to the capital?
수도로 가는 길인가요?
However, the noble taste
그러나 고귀한 맛
is it hard
어려워
to kill the King of Qin who was below
밑에 있는 진왕을 죽이려고
the protection of thousands of soldiers?
수천 명의 군인을 보호한다고요?
Young Master Liu has a good way?
Liu 젊은 스승님 좋은 방법이 있나요?
His Highness can take unexpected actions.
전하는 예상치 못한 행동을 취할 수 있습니다.
Start with Cui Lin.
추이린부터 시작해 보세요.
Make him worry first.
먼저 그를 걱정하게 만드세요.
After he was worried,
고민 끝에,
he will make mistakes.
그는 실수를 할 것입니다.
At that time,
그때에,
Your Honor can take this opportunity
재판장님은 이 기회를 놓치지 마세요
to kill the King of Qin.
진왕을 죽이려고
This is indeed a good way.
이것은 참으로 좋은 방법입니다.
However, it is difficult to
그러나, 그것은 어렵다
implement it.
그것을 구현하십시오.
Do not worry.
걱정 하지마.
Since I suggest this way,
제가 이런 방법을 제안한 이후로,
I will take people there
나는 사람들을 그곳으로 데려갈 것이다
to help the noble.
귀족을 돕기 위해.
Once this is done,
이 작업이 완료되면,
How can I thank Mr. Young Liu?
Young Liu 씨에게 어떻게 감사를 표해야 할까요 ?
I do want to
나는 원한다
serve the noble.
귀족을 섬기십시오.
I don't want anything else.
나는 다른 것을 원하지 않습니다.
I just hope the noble
나는 단지 고귀한 것을 바란다
move a group of people
한 무리의 사람들을 움직이다
for me to direct.
나한테 지시하라고.
Many days have passed.
많은 날이 지났습니다.
The King of Qin was inside the border
진왕은 국경 안에 있었다.
and we are out of bounds.
그리고 우리는 범위를 벗어났습니다.
Logically,
논리적으로,
not far.
멀지 않은.
King Qin is not making sense.
진왕(秦王)은 말이 안 된다.
He didn't come here
그 사람 여기 안 왔어
and don't send people either.
사람도 보내지 마세요.
Lieutenant.
대장 보좌.
Speak up.
발언.
Is the King of Qin
진(秦)나라 왕인가
really angry?
정말 화가 났어?
Why are you so worried?
왜 그렇게 걱정해요?
King Qin is angry or not,
진왕이 화를 내든 말든,
what does it have to do with me?
그게 나와 무슨 상관이 있는 걸까?
Look at it.
보세요.
You are really close
당신은 정말 가깝습니다
with the previous King of Qin.
전 진왕과 함께.
Aren't you
그렇지 않나요?
have a misunderstanding
오해를 하다
for the sake of his great-grandson this time?
이번에는 증손자를 위해서?
Taozi, what's up with you today?
타오즈야, 오늘 무슨 일 있어?
You don't fly on a normal day.
당신은 보통 날에는 비행기를 타지 않습니다.
I just thought about this.
방금 이것에 대해 생각했습니다.
Is the King of Qin
진(秦)나라 왕인가
become ill?
병에 걸리다?
The weather has been changing lately.
최근 날씨가 변하고 있어요.
It was suddenly cold and hot.
갑자기 춥고 더워졌습니다.
I heard,
나는 들었다,
many people fell ill inside the border.
많은 사람들이 국경 안에서 병에 걸렸습니다.
Is Duo pun
듀오 말장난인가
caught a cold.
감기에 걸리다.
If you are worried about Xie Chang'er,
Xie Chang'er가 걱정된다면,
send medicine for him yourself.
그 사람에게 직접 약을 보내주세요.
So.
그래서.
I will not go
난 안가
Lieutenant.
대장 보좌.
If you don't care about King Qin,
진왕에게 관심이 없다면
I won't even care
난 신경도 안 쓸 거야
Is Duo.
듀오입니다.
I will not care about him.
나는 그 사람에 대해 신경 쓰지 않을 것입니다.
Taozi.
도자.
Taozi, you finally came.
도자야, 드디어 왔구나.
What did the lieutenant say?
중위는 뭐라고 말했습니까?
He is still the same.
그는 여전히 동일합니다.
I have been advising him for a long time.
나는 오랫동안 그에게 조언을 해왔습니다.
He also refused to mention the King of Qin.
그는 또한 진왕에 대한 언급도 거부했습니다.
What should we do?
우리는 무엇을 해야 합니까?
When I came here,
내가 여기 왔을 때,
Bao and everyone tell me
바오랑 다들 말해
to ask you
당신에게 물어보려고
reconciled the lieutenant and Mr. Shiqi.
중위와 Shiqi 씨를 화해했습니다.
You don't know
당신은 모른다
that Mr. Shiqi
그 Shiqi 씨
really angry now
지금 정말 화가 나
Before one o'clock every morning, he would wake up and practice swordsmanship.
그는 매일 새벽 1시가 되기 전에 일어나 검술을 연습했다.
He forced us to practice together.
그는 우리에게 함께 연습하도록 강요했습니다.
We practice sword and spear every day.
우리는 매일 검과 창을 연습합니다 .
If not,
그렇지 않다면,
we will practice formation at the army camp.
우리는 군대 캠프에서 대형 훈련을 할 것입니다 .
We can't take it anymore.
우리는 더 이상 참을 수 없습니다.
It's useless for you to tell me.
당신이 나에게 말해봤자 소용없어요.
I also
나도
no other way
다른 방법은 없어
to persuade you again.
다시 한번 설득해 보세요.
This is how.
이것이 방법입니다.
The King of Qin ordered
진왕이 명령했다.
pretending to be sick
아픈 척
With that,
그것으로,
I can ask ma'am
부인한테 물어봐도 돼요
to visit the King of Qin.
진왕을 만나러 갑니다.
If King Qin is willing to pretend to be sick,
진왕이 아픈 척 하려고 하면
he wouldn't even wake up early to practice swordsmanship every day.
그는 매일 검술을 연습하기 위해 일찍 일어나지도 않았습니다 .
What should we do?
우리는 무엇을 해야 합니까?
Bao.
바오.
How?
어떻게?
What did the Taoist say?
도교인은 뭐라고 말했는가?
Taozi gives an idea.
Taozi가 아이디어를 제시합니다.
However,
하지만,
it doesn't feel right.
기분이 좋지 않습니다.
If he refuses to pretend to be sick,
아픈 척을 거부한다면,
let's
하자
let him get a little sick.
그 사람이 조금 아프게 놔두세요.
Give this to him.
이것을 그에게 주세요.
He will get sick after eating it.
그는 그것을 먹고 나면 아플 것입니다.
At that time, I will tell you
그땐 내가 너에게 말해줄게
that the King of Qin fell ill and told him to visit the King of Qin.
진왕이 병이 나서 진왕을 찾아오라고 말했다.
This is not appropriate.
이는 적절하지 않습니다.
What is not appropriate?
적절하지 않은 것은 무엇입니까?
I think it fits perfectly.
제 생각에는 완벽하게 맞는 것 같아요.
Bao.
바오.
Is Duo.
듀오입니다.
You don't know
당신은 모른다
that Mr. Shiqi brought me
Shiqi 씨가 나에게 가져온 것
patrolling late at night.
늦은 밤 순찰 중.
At one o'clock this morning,
오늘 아침 한시쯤,
he surprised me
그 사람이 나를 놀라게 했어
and told me to practice swordsmanship with him.
그리고 같이 검술을 연습하자고 하더군요 .
I don't want to live
나는 살고 싶지 않다
in this way again.
또 이런 식으로.
Don't you want to take medicine?
약 먹고 싶지 않아?
I will take medicine.
나는 약을 먹을 것이다.
Bao.
바오.
It can't be like this. If...
이렇게는 있을 수 없습니다. 만약에...
If what?
그렇다면 무엇?
If he doesn't get sick again,
만약 그 사람이 다시 아프지 않는다면,
i will go crazy
나는 미칠 것이다
It's better if he gets sick.
그가 아프면 더 좋습니다.
If not, I will really go crazy.
안 그러면 정말 미칠 것 같아요.
Bao.
바오.
Place a sign.
표지판을 놓습니다.
Those who are pinched have medicine.
꼬집힌 사람에게는 약이 있습니다.
What is not pinched has no medicine.
꼬집지 않은 것은 약이 아니다.
Tuan Shiqi.
투안시치.
You've been practicing for a long time.
오랫동안 연습하셨네요.
You must be hungry.
배가 고프겠군요.
I had the kitchen make this.
주방에서 이렇게 만들었어요.
Eat it.
그것을 먹을.
Are kitchen people good at making snacks like this?
주방 사람들은 이런 간식을 잘 만드는 걸까요?
Isn't Sun Jing's cook
Sun Jing의 요리사가 아닌가?
still alive?
아직 살아 있나요?
I told him to do it.
나는 그에게 그렇게 하라고 말했습니다.
Try the cuisine.
요리를 맛보세요.
Look at this snack.
이 간식 좀 보세요.
Very delicate and beautiful.
매우 섬세하고 아름답습니다.
Try it.
시도 해봐.
Look.
바라보다.
Delicious.
맛있는.
Delicious, isn't it?
맛있지, 그렇지?
It's delicious.
이 맛있어요.
Why, Bao?
왜 그래, 바오?
Are you not well?
몸이 안 좋으세요?
Delicious.
맛있는.
We are good friends.
우리는 좋은 친구 야.
How dare you mistreat me.
감히 나를 학대하다니.
Bao.
바오.
Poisoning?
중독?
I used to be a counselor.
나는 상담사였습니다.
How dare you add poison
감히 독을 더하다니
in front of me?
내 앞에?
You forced me
당신은 나에게 강요
wake up early and sleep late.
일찍 일어나고 늦게 자세요.
We only practice swords and spears.
우리는 검과 창만 연습합니다.
How dare you change it
어떻게 감히 바꾸나요?
and tell me to eat a snack laced with poison?
독이 든 간식을 먹으라고 합니까 ?
I want to break up with you.
나는 당신과 헤어지고 싶다.
I want to break up with you!
너랑 헤어지고 싶어!
Young master.
젊은 주인님.
Really want to poison the lieutenant?
정말로 중위를 독살하고 싶나요?
Orang Jiesuo
오랑 지에쑤오
give us just one.
하나만 주세요.
He said, this is the most valuable secret medicine for them.
그는 이것이 그들에게 가장 귀중한 비약이라고 말했습니다.
After taking this medicine,
이 약을 복용한 후,
no signs of poisoning.
중독 징후가 없습니다.
People who eat it seem to get seriously ill.
그것을 먹는 사람들은 중병에 걸릴 것 같습니다.
Even the greatest healer cannot know for sure.
가장 위대한 치료사라도 확실히 알 수는 없습니다.
Without a cure,
치료법도 없이,
the person who eats it will die after a few days.
그것을 먹는 사람은 며칠 후에 죽을 것입니다.
If Ying didn't have any problems,
이영애에게 문제가 없었다면
Li Ni will not be confused.
Li Ni는 혼란스럽지 않을 것입니다.
If Li Ni is not confused,
리니가 혼란스럽지 않다면
we can't kill Li Ni
우리는 Li Ni를 죽일 수 없습니다
and couldn't kidnap Ying.
그리고 잉을 납치할 수도 없었어요.
Go away.
저리 가요.
Be careful.
조심하세요.
Of.
의.
Why, miss?
왜요, 아가씨?
Let me see.
어디 보자.
I have been uncomfortable since this morning.
오늘 아침부터 불편했어요.
My head hurts now.
지금 머리가 아파요.
It's hot.
그것은 뜨겁다.
Must be a fever.
발열이 있어야 합니다.
So,
그래서,
I have a fever.
내가 열이.
Bao.
바오.
Why are your skills backwards?
실력이 왜 뒤쳐지나요?
I couldn't beat you since before.
예전부터 난 당신을 이길 수 없었어요 .
After all,
결국,
I have had diarrhea for several days.
나는 며칠 동안 설사를 했습니다.
I have become weak. You didn't even let me go.
나는 약해졌습니다. 당신은 나를 놓아주지도 않았습니다.
You...
너...
Did you really do that?
정말 그랬나요?
Tuan Shiqi.
투안시치.
What?
무엇?
Taozi has come.
타오즈가 왔습니다.
He said, there is an emergency.
긴급상황이 발생했다고 하더군요.
I don't want to see him.
나는 그를 보고 싶지 않아요.
Mr. Shiqi, he has an emergency.
Shiqi 씨, 그에게 긴급 상황이 생겼습니다.
What's the anxiety?
불안은 무엇입니까?
If it's about the military,
군대 이야기라면,
tell him to write a letter
그에게 편지를 쓰라고 해라
and send it to our army.
그리고 우리 군대에 보내세요.
As an ally, would the King of Qin want to
동맹국으로서 진왕이 원할 것인가?
ignore it?
무시해?
Let me go!
날 보내줘!
King of Qin.
진(秦)나라 왕.
Why?
왜?
The lieutenant fell ill.
중위가 병에 걸렸습니다.
The situation is bad.
상황이 좋지 않습니다.
The lieutenant fell ill?
중위가 아팠나요?
Find a doctor.
의사를 찾으세요.
Why do you want to see me?
왜 나를 보고 싶어?
Since childhood, I checked the lieutenant's pulse.
어릴 때부터 중위의 맥박을 확인했습니다.
I understand his body condition.
나는 그의 몸 상태를 이해한다.
This time,
이 시간,
the situation is strange.
상황이 이상해요.
He suddenly had a high fever.
그는 갑자기 고열을 느꼈다.
I do acupuncture and give medicine,
침치료도 하고 약도 주고,
but not effective.
하지만 효과적이지 않습니다.
Today,
오늘,
lieutenant already
이미 중위
is in a coma.
혼수상태에 빠져있습니다.
Honourable.
존경스럽습니다.
Hurry up to see him.
서둘러 그를 만나세요.
I've never seen it
나는 그것을 본 적이 없다
this strange terrible disease.
이 이상하고 끔찍한 질병.
You can't even treat him,
당신은 그 사람을 치료할 수도 없어요.
so you should find a doctor.
그러니 의사를 찾아야 해요.
You...
너...
King Qin's coldness.
진왕의 차가움.
Anything,
아무것,
Cui Family Army
추이 가문 군대
is an ally of the Zhenxi Army, right?
진시군 의 동맹 자죠?
Since we conspired,
우리가 공모한 이후로,
you shouldn't treat him like this.
그 사람을 이렇게 대하면 안 돼요 .
You are cruel.
당신은 잔인합니다.
Tuan Shiqi.
투안시치.
Taozi.
도자.
Taozi!
도자!
You...
너...
Why are you so cruel?
왜 그렇게 잔인합니까?
Don't pretend anymore.
더 이상 척하지 마세요.
I know
알아요
about your tricks
당신의 트릭에 대해
You want to make me sick,
당신은 나를 아프게 만들고 싶어,
but did not succeed.
그러나 성공하지 못했습니다.
So, you made him fall ill,
그래서 당신은 그를 병들게 만들었고,
not?
아니다?
Nothing to do with me this time.
이번에는 나와 관련이 없습니다.
I swear.
맹세해요.
(It's good to go see him.)
(그를 만나러 가는 것이 좋다.)
(What if he really is sick?)
(그 사람이 정말 아프면 어쩌지?)
How much.
얼마나 많이.
You must survive.
당신은 살아남아야합니다.
I told people to ride fast horses
나는 사람들에게 빠른 말을 타라고 말했어요
to report to the commander in chief.
총사령관에게 보고합니다.
So...
그래서...
He will arrive soon.
그는 곧 도착할 것이다.
Miss must survive.
미스는 살아남아야 합니다.
Tuan Shiqi.
투안시치.
I'm outside.
나는 밖에 있다.
The moon is shining and there are less stars tonight.
오늘 밤에는 달이 빛나고 별이 적습니다.
Master Shiqi, let's go.
Shiqi 선생님, 가세요.
Go on patrol.
순찰을 가세요.
Aren't you busy talking?
얘기하느라 바쁘지 않니?
that you want to sleep?
자고 싶다고?
You find various excuses so you don't have to patrol.
순찰을 하지 않아도 되도록 다양한 핑계를 찾습니다 .
Why?
왜?
You are very proactive today.
오늘은 매우 적극적이군요.
Tonight is not the same.
오늘 밤은 같지 않습니다.
I am energetic.
나는 활력이 넘칩니다.
Let me accompany you on patrol
순찰에 동행하겠습니다
so you don't do anything else.
그러니 다른 일은 하지 마세요.
What will I do?
나는 무엇을 할 것인가?
If you don't want to do anything,
아무것도 하고 싶지 않다면,
it's still good.
아직 괜찮아요.
Let's go.
갑시다.
I will be with you all night.
나는 밤새도록 당신과 함께 있을 것입니다.
Check the presence of soldiers at six in the morning.
아침 6시에 군인의 존재를 확인하십시오.
Let's go.
갑시다.
Go away.
저리 가요.
Tonight,
오늘 밤,
we will patrol
우리는 순찰할 것이다
in all corners.
모든 구석에.
How much.
얼마나 많이.
Taozi.
도자.
Taozi, I have cooked medicine.
도자님, 제가 약을 끓였습니다.
I obey what you say
나는 당신이 말하는 것에 순종합니다
to buy this medicine
이 약을 사려고
at a nearby drug store.
근처 약국에서.
Then, I sat in the kitchen and cooked this medicine myself.
그리고 나는 부엌에 앉아 이 약을 직접 요리했습니다.
The timing is right.
타이밍이 맞습니다.
How much.
얼마나 많이.
The medicine is ready, miss.
약은 준비됐어요, 아가씨.
Give me.
나에게주세요.
Miss, the medicine is ready.
아가씨, 약이 준비됐어요.
Miss will be cured after eating it.
미스는 그것을 먹고 나을 것입니다.
How much.
얼마나 많이.
Miss, please.
아가씨, 제발요.
Open mouth.
입을 벌려라.
Miss will be cured after eating it.
미스는 그것을 먹고 나을 것입니다.
How much.
얼마나 많이.
I really have no other way.
정말 다른 방법이 없어요.
Please take medicine, miss.
약 드세요, 아가씨.
How much.
얼마나 많이.
Taozi.
도자.
I will call Mr. Shiqi now.
지금 Shiqi 씨에게 전화하겠습니다.
I will force him
나는 그에게 강요할 것이다
come this time.
이번에 오세요.
Do not go.
가지 마.
He's a cold person.
그는 차가운 사람입니다.
Why did you call him to come?
왜 그 사람을 오라고 부르셨나요?
So.
그래서.
Surely he didn't know
분명 그 사람은 몰랐을 거야
that Lieutenant He's condition is dire.
그 중위의 상태가 심각하다고요.
Mr. Shiqi is not that kind of person.
Shiqi 씨는 그런 사람이 아닙니다.
Please let me take care of you here.
여기서는 제가 당신을 돌보도록 해주세요.
I will command the whole army
내가 전군을 지휘하리라
to increase alertness.
주의력을 높이기 위해.
He is very sick now.
그는 지금 매우 아프다.
Can't let outsiders know
외부인에게 알릴 수 없다
and take a chance.
그리고 기회를 잡으세요.
Good.
좋은.
Oh yes.
바로 이거 야.
After I got home,
집에 도착한 후,
you can go back first
너 먼저 돌아가도 돼
Otherwise, you will miss the attendance check in the army.
그렇지 않으면 군대 출석체크를 놓치게 됩니다 .
So.
그래서.
I am with you here.
나는 여기에 당신과 함께 있습니다.
You are from the Zhenxi Army.
당신은 Zhenxi 군대 출신입니다.
If the commander-in-chief returns
총사령관이 돌아오면
and see the condition of the lady,
그리고 그 부인의 상태를 보고,
I'm worried that he will kill you.
그 사람이 당신을 죽일까봐 걱정됩니다 .
Young master.
젊은 주인님.
How?
어떻게?
King Qin hasn't come out yet.
진왕은 아직 나오지 않았습니다.
I don't think it's right.
나는 그것이 옳지 않다고 생각한다.
I didn't think Li Ni
리니는 아닌 것 같았는데
so cold.
너무 추워요.
Ying looked at him wrongly.
잉은 그를 잘못 보았다.
Young master.
젊은 주인님.
The lieutenant had been poisoned for three days.
중위는 3일 동안 독살당했습니다 .
If he doesn't take the antidote tonight,
오늘 밤 해독제를 먹지 않으면
his life will be affected
그의 인생은 영향을 받을 것이다
even if he eats the cure in the morning.
아침에 치료제를 먹어도 .
Wait again.
다시 기다려주세요.
Tuan Shiqi.
투안시치.
Do not go.
가지 마.
It's only one o'clock in the morning.
이제 겨우 새벽 1시입니다.
What are you doing back?
뒤로 뭐하는 거야?
We have patrolled all the places. Why do you want to stay here?
우리는 모든 곳을 순찰했습니다. 왜 여기에 머물고 싶나요?
Patrolling again.
다시 순찰 중입니다.
Didn't we promise?
우리 약속하지 않았나요?
I will accompany you until the morning.
아침까지 동행하겠습니다.
I have something else.
나는 다른 것을 가지고 있습니다.
What thing?
무슨 일이?
I haven't read the letter
나는 편지를 읽지 않았다
sent from the capital.
수도에서 보냈습니다.
You can read it tomorrow.
내일 읽으시면 됩니다.
It is not an emergency letter.
긴급편지는 아닙니다.
I want to sleep.
나는 자고 싶다.
How did you scold me a few nights ago?
며칠 전에 어떻게 나를 꾸짖었나요 ?
Not tired.
피곤하지 않아요.
We are not sleepy.
우리는 졸리지 않습니다.
You did it on purpose, didn't you?
일부러 그랬지, 그렇지?
You are right.
당신 말이 맞아요.
I'm deliberately.
나는 일부러.
Good. Let's continue.
좋은. 계속합시다.
Proceed.
진행하다.
- Go away.
- 저리 가요.
Go away.
저리 가요.
You can't stop me, can you?
당신은 나를 막을 수 없습니다, 그렇죠?
Young master, it's almost dawn.
젊은 스승님, 이제 곧 새벽이 왔습니다.
I don't think it's right.
나는 그것이 옳지 않다고 생각한다.
Ying is really smart,
잉은 정말 똑똑해요.
but he trusted the wrong person.
하지만 그는 사람을 잘못 믿었습니다.
Tonight, the Cui Family Army has increased vigilance.
오늘 밤, 추이 가문 군대의 경계심이 강화되었습니다.
If we wait until dawn,
새벽까지 기다리면,
it's hard for me to enter.
내가 들어가기가 어렵습니다.
This is the cure.
이것이 치료법입니다.
Go away.
저리 가요.
Let Ying take the medicine first.
Ying이 먼저 약을 먹도록 하세요.
Of.
의.
Taozi.
도자.
Why did King Qin come?
진왕은 왜 왔는가?
Is your lieutenant
당신의 중위입니까?
did you fall sick?
아팠어?
Only healthy lieutenant.
건강한 중위 만.
No need to worry, your honor.
걱정하지 마세요, 재판장님.
Is he really sick?
그 사람 정말 아픈 걸까?
No lah.
아니, 그게 다야.
Your Highness, please keep your temper.
전하, 화를 내십시오.
This is the Cui Family Army camp.
이것은 Cui 가족 군대 캠프입니다.
If the noble continues to do this,
귀족이 계속 이런 짓을 한다면,
I will tell people
나는 사람들에게 말할 것이다
drive away the noble.
귀족을 몰아내세요.
Taozi.
도자.
Who are you talking to outside?
밖에서 누구랑 얘기하고 있어?
How much.
얼마나 많이.
Slowly.
느리게.
Mari.
마리.
Let me see.
어디 보자.
I am fine.
괜찮아요.
You must be worried.
당신은 걱정해야합니다.
I am really worried.
정말 걱정됩니다.
Ying.
잉.
You did get sick.
당신은 아팠어요.
Which one hurts?
어느 쪽이 아프나요?
are you ok now
괜찮아요
King Qin, don't be like that.
진왕님, 그러지 마세요.
It's just a mild illness.
그냥 가벼운 질병이에요.
No need to worry.
걱정할 필요 없어.
Taozi.
도자.
You're out for a second.
당신은 잠시 외출 중입니다.
I want to talk
나는 이야기하고 싶다
with the King of Qin.
진왕과 함께.
How much.
얼마나 많이.
You just woke up.
당신은 일어났다.
Let me accompany you here.
여기에 동행하겠습니다.
It's ok. Do not worry.
괜찮아요. 걱정 하지마.
Go away.
저리 가요.
Ying.
잉.
You hate me because I cheated on you.
내가 당신을 속였기 때문에 당신은 나를 싫어합니다 .
These several days,
요 며칠,
I also think a lot.
나 역시 많은 생각을 한다.
Even if this happens again,
이런 일이 또 발생하더라도
I will still do that.
나는 여전히 그렇게 할 것이다.
I don't regret it.
나는 그것을 후회하지 않는다.
Because I think
내 생각엔
whether he is the great-grandson of the real majesty
그가 진짜 폐하의 증손자인지 아닌지
or a fake one,
아니면 가짜거나,
It's not worth it for you to sacrifice for him.
당신이 그를 위해 희생하는 것은 가치가 없습니다 .
You are sick now.
당신은 지금 아프다.
Do not discuss this again.
이 문제를 다시 논의하지 마십시오.
When I have a fever
열이 날 때
and didn't realize a few days before,
며칠 전에는 깨닫지 못했지만,
I hope that you can come visit me.
당신이 나를 방문할 수 있기를 바랍니다 .
When someone gets sick,
누군가가 아프면,
he will become weak.
그는 약해질 것이다.
My mother died when I was little.
제가 어렸을 때 어머니가 돌아가셨어요 .
I have less family members too.
나도 가족이 적다.
Now, besides dad,
이제 아빠 외에
you are the closest to me.
당신은 나에게 가장 가깝습니다.
At that time, I thought
그때 나는 생각했다.
that if you come to see me,
네가 나를 보러 오면,
then it proves that
그럼 그걸 증명해
you care more about me
당신은 나에게 더 관심이 있습니다
from other things
다른 것들로부터
and others.
다른 사람.
If you come,
니가 온다면,
I can explain
나는 설명할 수 있다
that's up to you
그건 당신에게 달렸습니다
even if I'm angry.
화가 나더라도.
With this, you can too
이것으로 당신도 할 수 있습니다
understand my feelings next time.
다음에는 내 기분을 이해해줘.
However, you did not come.
그러나 당신은 오지 않았습니다.
I know
알아요
that you still scold me
네가 아직도 나를 꾸짖고 있다고
I'm not scolding you.
나는 당신을 꾸짖는 것이 아닙니다.
In my heart,
내 마음 속에,
you are more important than anyone else.
당신은 누구보다 중요합니다.
Honourable,
존경합니다,
don't fool me again
다시는 나를 속이지 마세요
I also want to tell you something
나도 너한테 하고 싶은 말이 있어
honestly.
솔직히.
I want to tell you
나는 당신에게 말하고 싶다
that I don't care
난 상관하지 않는다고
title of King of Qin
진왕의 칭호
or the commander in chief.
아니면 총사령관.
I just want to finish Concubine Xiao's order.
난 그냥 후궁 샤오의 명령을 끝내고 싶을 뿐이야 .
Then, I want to go back to Laolan Border
그럼 라오란 국경으로 돌아가고 싶어
with you
너와 함께
We can enjoy the sky there.
우리는 그곳에서 하늘을 즐길 수 있어요.
Shiqi.
시치.
You can't go back.
당신은 돌아갈 수 없습니다.
your father
아버지
is the current emperor.
현 황제입니다.
Sun Jing is dead, the situation is decided.
Sun Jing이 죽었고 상황이 결정되었습니다.
Both your brothers
두 형제 모두
just like a wild animal.
마치 야생동물처럼.
Do you want to submit?
제출하시겠습니까?
our country to them?
우리 나라가 그들에게?
I have said.
나는 말했다.
After I saved his great-grandson,
그의 증손자를 구한 뒤,
I will persuade him
나는 그를 설득할 것이다
to appoint his great-grandson as crown prince.
자신의 증손자를 왕세자로 임명하기 위해서다.
How old is his great-grandson this year?
그의 증손자는 올해 몇 살입니까?
His great-grandson is still young.
그의 증손자는 아직 어리다.
How are his qualifications and talents?
그의 자격과 재능은 어떻습니까?
If he becomes a talentless person
만약 그 사람이 재능 없는 사람이 된다면
after he grew up,
그가 성장한 후,
how does he want to lead the country?
그는 어떻게 나라를 이끌고 싶습니까?
His great-grandson is a legitimate descendant.
그의 증손자는 적법한 후손이다.
He should inherit the throne.
그는 왕위를 물려받아야 합니다.
After all, he is talented.
결국 그는 재능이 있습니다.
There are many more dignitaries
더 많은 고위 인사가 있습니다
will help him.
그를 도울 것입니다.
He will succeed.
그는 성공할 것이다.
Are both your brothers
둘 다 네 형제야?
will let his great-grandson live to adulthood?
증손자가 성인이 될 때까지 살게 해줄 것인가?
Anything,
아무것,
you feel that
당신은 그것을 느낀다
I have to compete for this throne.
나는 이 왕좌를 위해 경쟁해야 한다.
That's right.
좋아요.
Because I think you are the most suitable
내 생각엔 당신이 가장 적합하다고 생각하니까
to lead this country.
이 나라를 이끌기 위해.
You are generous and care about this country.
당신은 관대하고 이 나라에 관심을 가지고 있습니다.
You have compassion for the people.
당신은 사람들에 대한 연민을 가지고 있습니다.
You have great military achievements
당신은 훌륭한 군사적 업적을 가지고 있습니다.
and great in controlling the army.
군대를 통제하는 데 능숙합니다.
You restored the kingdom
당신은 왕국을 회복하셨습니다
and put down the rebellion.
그리고 반란을 진압하십시오.
If you are appointed crown prince,
만약 당신이 왕세자로 임명된다면 ,
magnifier in the balirung draw
Balirung 추첨의 돋보기
will not object.
반대하지 않을 것입니다.
Without a dispute in the draw,
추첨 시 분쟁 없이,
people can live happily.
사람들은 행복하게 살 수 있습니다.
Shiqi.
시치.
You will be
당신은 될 것입니다
good and responsible emperor.
착하고 책임감 있는 황제.
If you become emperor,
당신이 황제가 된다면,
this country will be peaceful and prosperous
이 나라는 평화롭고 번영할 것이다
for decades to come.
앞으로 수십 년 동안.
Everyone has their own ambitions.
모든 사람은 자신만의 야망을 가지고 있습니다.
There are people who want to control the whole country,
나라 전체를 장악하려는 사람들이 있고 ,
but I just want to keep my promise.
하지만 나는 단지 약속을 지키고 싶을 뿐입니다.
When the situation stabilizes,
상황이 안정되면,
I want to protect
나는 보호하고 싶다
Laolan border with you.
당신과 함께 Laolan 국경.
What if I
만약 내가
refused to follow you to the Laolan Border?
라오라 국경까지 당신을 따라가는 것을 거부했다 고요?
♪If you've forgotten the twinkling light♪
♪반짝이는 빛을 잊으셨다면♪
♪Tunggu kenangan♪
♪퉁구 케난간♪
♪Shattered and sunk♪
♪부서져 가라앉았어♪
♪The spots that remain on your heart♪
♪당신의 마음속에 남아있는 얼룩들 ♪
♪Penarikan itu♪
♪페나리칸 이투♪
♪It's my objection♪
♪이의가 있어요♪
♪If longing is never left behind♪
♪그리움이 결코 버리지 않는다면♪
♪Longing to go back to the earliest times♪
♪ 가장 옛날로 돌아가고 싶은 그리움 ♪
♪The warmth that fate once had♪
♪운명이 가졌던 따뜻함 ♪
♪I want to keep it for you♪
♪당신을 위해 간직하고 싶어요♪
♪If love still remembers♪
♪사랑이 아직도 기억한다면♪
♪We once promised♪
♪한번 약속했었지♪
♪Even though love hurts me♪
♪사랑이 나를 아프게 해도♪
♪I must live for you too♪
♪나도 당신을 위해 살아야 해요♪
♪Following faces in memories♪
♪추억 속 얼굴을 따라가다♪
♪Waiting is my obsession♪
♪기다리는 것이 나의 집착♪
♪If love still remembers♪
♪사랑이 아직도 기억한다면♪
♪A promise kept for you♪
♪당신을 위한 약속♪
♪Terbalikkan karma♪
♪테르발리칸 카르마♪
♪Loving for you without regret♪
♪후회없이 사랑합니다♪
♪I'm willing to leave it for you♪
♪당신에게 맡기고 싶습니다♪
♪I'm always waiting for you to answer me♪
♪항상 답변을 기다리고 있어요 ♪
♪If love still remembers♪
♪사랑이 아직도 기억한다면♪
♪A promise kept for you♪
♪당신을 위한 약속♪
♪Terbalikkan karma♪
♪테르발리칸 카르마♪
♪Loving for you without regret♪
♪후회없이 사랑합니다♪
♪I'm willing to leave it for you♪
♪당신에게 맡기고 싶습니다♪
♪I'm always waiting for you to answer me♪
♪항상 답변을 기다리고 있어요 ♪